Miles, Rufus E., Jr.; Papers apap048
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty at Princeton's Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs, 1966-1975; 5; 22 folders
  - Unpublished papers by Miles on management, 1969 (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 25)
  - Papers connected to Miles' unpublished essay: "Is Leadership Teachable?", 1969 April (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 26)
  - Note on and copies of Miles' article: "The Pathology of Institutional Breakdown".Journal of Higher Education XL, 1969 May (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 27)
  - Documents from a conference paper: "Policy Options in Coping with Problems of Poverty", 1969 June 18 (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 28)
  - Materials regarding Miles course on "Poverty and Public Policy", 1969 (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 29)
  - Papers related to Miles' "Non-Subservient Public Servant" and editorial in Public Administration Review, 1970 November-1970 December (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 30)
  - Documents dealing with Miles seminar on "Issues of Government Organization", 1972 January (Box 2 (5-Rufus Miles Activities as a Member of the Faculty ), Folder 31)
- Rufus Miles Writings and Activities while a Senior Fellow at the Woodrow Wilson School, Princeton University, 1976-1982; 6; 26 folders
  This series encompasses lectures, published articles, materials related to conference participation on various public policy issues. In particular it contains items related to the Presidency of Jimmy Carter namely Carter's Welfare and Civil Service Reform Programs. It also holds a copy of Miles' testimony before Congress regarding Social Security Organization (Jan.1984) and materials related to the Rockefeller Public Service Awards Program.
  - Personnel papers, photos, miscellaneous items for this period, 1975-1982
  - Rockefeller Public Service Awards Program, 1974-1982; 7 folders
    Including Miles' leading role in reforming the nature of that program (1975).
  - Papers pertaining to lectures given at private colleges (Carleton, Guildford, Hamilton, Hiram, Middlebury) sponsored by the Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1974-1978
  - Documents related to a Policy task Force on Youth Employment and two conferences on that same subject, 1976
  - Notes regarding and copies of Miles' "Considerations for a President Bent on Reorganization"Public Administration Review, Vol. 37(2), 1977 March-1977 April
  - Materials related to Miles' opinion on and other views of President Carter's Welfare Reform Program, 1977-1978
  - Documents related to Miles view of President Carter's Civil Service Reform program including correspondence with Alan K. Campbell, Chairman of the Civil Service Commission, and a letter from Jimmy Carter urging support, 1977-1978
  - Correspondence regarding and copies of Miles' "The Origin and Meaning of Miles' Law"Public Administration Review, 38, 1978 September-1978 October
  - Correspondence pertaining to and copies of Miles' "Six Other Maxims of Management"Organizational Dynamics, 1979 Summer
  - Materials regarding Miles' and others opinions on management including a proposal to the National Academy of Public administration titled "A Typology of Management", 1979; 2 folders
  - Papers related to actuarial forecasting and an "earnings test" for Social security, 1975-1979
    Including his statement before HEW's Advisory Council on social Security (1979).
  - Documents pertaining to and copy of Miles' "The Abominable Myth of 48% Waste" appearing untitled in the Public Administration Times, 1981 April 15
  - Copy of Miles' paper "Rethinking some Premises of the Senior Executive Service" read at a Brookings Institute Seminar: "Dialogue on the Public Service", 1981 May 6
  - Papers related to the Woodrow Wilson's School's Public Management Task Force and Mid-Career Task force, 1980-1981
  - Miscellaneous correspondence with Richard Nathan, 1979-1982
  - Miscellaneous correspondence etc., 1977-1982
    Including Miles letter of resignation (1982).
  - Related matter after retirement, Undated; 2 folders
    Testimony before Congressional Panel on Social Security Organization (January 13, 1984) and related materials to this testimony and the history of Social Security in general. *excluding most materials concerning his work in creating a cabinet level Department of Education (see Series 4).